Ysmenport
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Looks tasty...
（アーミラ）
おいしそう…
（ファバロ）
おい 何やってんだ
Hey! What are you doing?
Let's get going.
さっさと行くぞ
You never said anything about having to sail to Helheim.
君 ヘルヘイムに行くために
海を渡るなんて言ってなかった
Uh, well...
うっ それは…
What did you just say?
（ファバロ）
今 何て言った？
That they got some of the finest booze there?
（バッカス）
あそこには とびきりうまい酒が…
I don't mean that!
じゃなくて！
Do you know how to get to Helheim?
知ってんのか？
ヘルヘイムへの道を
Don't you know who I am?
俺を誰だと思ってやがる？
I'm God with a capital G.
か… み… さま…
だあ！
And don't you forget it.
バカヤロー
I remembered an even easier way to get there, that's all!
もっと便利で簡単な道を
思い出したのさ
That's why we're here lookin' for a boat to Helheim.
だから こうして
ヘルヘイムに行く船を
探してんだろうが
You don't believe me again?
また 信じてねえのか？
Look me in the eye.
俺の目を見ろ
これが うそをついてる男の目に…
Do these look like the eyes of a liar?
I'm waiting for sunrises again
Rise up, rise up, rise up
Let me see the sun
Rage of Bahamut
（男Ａ）
ヘルヘイムに行く船？
Rage of Bahamut
知らねえな
（男Ｂ）
ヘルヘイム？
Rage of Bahamut
それって うまいのかい？
（女の子）知らな～い
（男の子）知らねえよ
Rage of Bahamut
People always say
"black or white," but the world is so gray
Even angels and demons were once the son of God I praise
temee no gen'in wa temee no naka kara
You're the catalyst for your own demise
zenbu hikurumete omae no saga
It's inherent to your being
kizuku koro ni wa mou you're in a coffin
But by the time you realize, you're in a coffin
It's too late if you want to do something
What the hell is wrong with me?
I can't remember what I wanted to be
Tick, Tack this is what I found
I can see the keys are scattered around
kono yoru ga aketemo nanika kawaru wake ja nee sa
Even though a new day dawns, nothing's gonna change
Yes, I know; yes, I know that I...
I'm the only one
who can save myself
I'll never forget
All I wanna be is me
A boat that goes to Helheim? Never heard of one.
Helheim?
Does it taste good?
Don't know!
No idea!
（アーミラ）
どの船？
Where's the boat?
Just chill out for a second.
（ファバロ）
そ… そう慌てんなって
Maybe it's just not here yet.
まだ 港に着いてねえのかもな
That lousy ol' Bacchus. Did he give me a bogus tip?
（ファバロ）
バッカスのヤツ
ガセネタ教えやがったのか？
Looks tasty...
おいしそう…
This is bad.
（ファバロ）
マズいぞ～
Amira's gonna figure out I've been lying unless I do something, and fast.
このままだと
アーミラに俺のついた うそが…
Wanna go to Helheim, do ya?
（ヨギ）
ヘルヘイムに行きたいんだって？
The boat's this-a-way.
船なら こっちだぜ
Oh, wow! Silly me! It's that-a-way!
なんだあ！　俺様としたことが
ハッハ！　そっちか～
What a relief.
助かったあ…
They lost them?
（アザゼル）
見失った？
They did keep their eyes and noses on them all the way to Nebelville.
（ケルベロス）
ネブルビルまでは
ちゃんと見張っていたのに～
Yeah, yeah!
But their scent suddenly vanished, woof!
（メス犬）
突然 においが消えたワン
（オス犬）
不思議だワン
It's a mystery, woof!
（パズズ）
ハンッ！
犬っころなんぞに頼るからだ
This is what you get for relying on some mangy mutts!
The cat's hissing about something, woof!
（オス犬）
猫が何か ほざいてるワン
（メス犬）
ニャーニャー うるさいワン
He's annoying, woof!
What did you say?!
（パズズ）
何だと！
Stop it, all of you.
（アザゼル）
やめろ お前たち
Someone must have intervened.
恐らく
何者かの邪魔が入ったのだろう
Either the gods, one of their human pets,
神か 神に飼われた人間か
or perhaps...
もしくは…
Wait, are you suggesting it was
someone opposed to Lord Lucifer?
（パズズ）
おい まさか
ルシフェル様に敵対するヤツが？
It's possible.
（ケルベロス）ありえるかも
（２匹）ワン！
Since ol' Satan is resting in peace, the God Key could play a big part in the struggle for his place.
ずっと眠りっぱなしの
サタンちゃんの後継争いに
“神の鍵”は すっごく重要だもの
Have the dogs resume their search.
（アザゼル）
犬どもに探索を続けさせろ
You, too, Pazuzu.
パズズもだ
Just where is that girl headed?
あの女…
一体 どこへ向かっている？
Yep! Here we are!
（ファバロ）
これだよ これ！
This is the boat to Helheim!
こいつが ヘルヘイムに行く船！
Celephales
------------------------------- -------------------------------
Right?
なんだよな？
This is the Celephales.
セレファレス号
And that fellow over there is her captain.
で… あそこにいるのが
船長だ
（ファバロ）
ハッハッハッハ…
Amon, you bastard! You're alive?!
アモン！
てめえ 生きてやがったのか！
That's my line, Favaro!
（アモン）
そりゃ こっちの…
セリフだ ファバロ！
What in tarnation are you doin' here?!
こんな所で何してやがる！
Who's that? Your mother?
誰？　お母さん？
Hell no!
（２人）
違(ちげ)えよ！
Been three years, huh?
３年ぶりか
What're ya up to these days?
今は何やってんだ？
Why aren't you following in your old man's footsteps?
なぜ 親父(おやじ)さんの後を継がねえ？
バロッサも望んでいたはずだろ
That's what Barossa would've wanted.
I dunno.
どうかな
I'm not really cut out to be
a bandit leader like my old man was.
俺は親父のような
盗賊たちを束ねて
上に立つ器じゃねえし
Being an "honorable thief" just isn't my thing.
義賊ってガラでもねえ
I prefer being in business for myself. It doesn't cramp my style.
１人で伸び伸び商売してるほうが
よっぽど性に合ってんのさ
In that case, who's she?
じゃあ あの娘は？
What's a bounty hunter
dragging around a young girl for?
賞金稼ぎが
何だって若い女を連れてやがる？
Well, some stuff came up. You know how it is.
（ファバロ）
まあ ちょっとした災難っつうか…
Have you seen this man?
（カイザル）
この男を見かけなかったか？
Yeah. He was just looking for a boat.
ああ こいつなら
さっき 船を探してたぜ
A boat headed where?!
（カイザル）
どこに向かう船だ！
I-I'm not sure. But he's probably long gone by now.
（男Ａ）
さ… さあな
もう この港には
いねえんじゃねえか？
What a shame.
（リタ）
残念でした
It seems like we're too late.
手遅れだったみたいね
Why are you following me around?
なぜ 私につきまとう？
To pass the time.
（リタ）
暇潰し
I'm only kidding.
冗談よ
I was all alone in that village for so long, you know?
あの村には
ずっと 私一人しかいなかったもの
Plus, I have no reason to stay there anymore.
とどまる理由もなくなったし
What are you going to do?
あんたは どうするの？
Isn't it obvious?
（カイザル）
決まっている！
たとえヤツが
地の果てまで逃げようとも
I'm going to catch him, even if he flees to the ends of the earth!
必ず…
この手で！
You really hate him, don't you?
（リタ）
よっぽど憎いのね あの男が
How come?
どうして？
Well, it's—
（カイザル）
それは…
Sir Knight!
（ヨギ）騎士の旦那
（カイザル）ん？
You're looking for someone, I hear?
（ヨギ）
探し人… だって？
That dream again?
また あの夢かよ…
Doesn't look tasty.
おいしくなさそう…
You there. The catch-and-release fisher-demon.
（ファバロ）
そこで キャッチ･アンド･リリース
してる悪魔
Does this look familiar to you?
こいつを知ってっか？
（アーミラ）
アヒル？
A duck?
No!
ちっげえよ！
もっと こう でっかくてだな…
It's, like, huge and, you know...
（アーミラ）
ワニ？
An alligator?
Hell no!
だ～か～ら～
It breathes fire and burns whole towns and stuff like that to a crisp!
口から炎を吐いて
町だろうが何だろうが
全部 燃やしちまうようなヤツだ！
Doesn't seem tasty.
おいしくなさそう…
Are you honestly that hungry?
どんだけ腹ペコなんだよ
Favaro...
（アモン）
ファバロ
How's about a drink?
軽く 一杯やんねえか？
うまい肴(さかな)もあるぜ
I've got some tasty eats, too.
Ooh, I was just feeling a bit parched!
いいね！
ちょうど喉が渇いてたとこだ
おい こら！
Hey, you!
Wait up!
待ちやがれ！
Dagonia
------------------------------- -------------------------------
Tell me what you were about to say.
（リタ）
さっきの話 聞かせなさいよ
You're awfully curious for a dead person.
（カイザル）
死人のくせに好奇心が強いな
Favaro and I were childhood friends, actually.
ファバロ…
ヤツとは幼なじみだった
Do you still remember?
（アモン）
覚えてるか？
That day we did our final job with Barossa,
バロッサと俺たちの最後の仕事
stealing the tribute to the king...
王への献上品を盗んだ
あの日のことを
I belonged to a family of knights. His was a carpenter family.
（カイザル）
私は騎士の家
ヤツは大工の家
身分は違えども
私たちはウマが合い
Despite our differences in status, we got along well and spent much time together.
長い時間を共にした
I thought we were best friends,
親友だと思っていた
so I told him about my father without any suspicions.
だから 父のことも疑いなく話した
なのに…
Yet...
He had deceived me!
ヤツは… 私を だましていた
He hid the fact he was the son of a thief
盗賊の息子であることを隠し
and waited for his chance to get information out of me!
情報を引き出す機会を
狙っていたのだ！
He made a complete fool out of me and sabotaged my father's mission.
そして 私は
まんまと あの男に ほだされ
父の任務を…
But my old man died.
だが 親父は死んじまった
（アモン）
盗んだ宝石には
強い魔力が宿っていたのさ
The jewels we stole contained powerful magic,
and it called forth a horrific demon.
そいつが とんでもねえ悪魔を
呼び寄せちまった
（アモン）
仲間も全員 皆殺し
Everyone was slaughtered.
俺だけが生き残った
I was the only one who survived.
It was your old man who saved me, in fact.
お前の親父さんが
助けてくれたおかげでな
Favaro, I'll do whatever it takes to get you two to Helheim.
ファバロ
お前たちは必ず
ヘルヘイムまで送り届けてやるよ
Thanks.
（ファバロ）
頼んだぜ
What's an "old man"?
（アーミラ）
“オヤジ”って 何？
Old man? There were plenty back at the port.
（ファバロ）
オヤジ？
港に たくさんいただろ
No! I mean the "old man" you were talking about earlier!
（アーミラ）
違う！　さっき 君が言っていた
オヤジのこと
Oh, we were talking about my father.
（ファバロ）
ああ ありゃ 俺の父親の話だ
Father?
ちちおや？
You got one too, do you not?!
お前にだって いんだろ？　父親
知らない
I don't know.
What is a father like?
（アーミラ）
“ちちおや”って どんな人？
I'm not sure how to answer that.
（ファバロ）
どんなって言われても…
Your father is your male parent. Your mom's husband, y'know?
父親は男の親で
お前の母ちゃんの旦那だろ？
My mother's... husband?
（アーミラ）
だんな？　お母さんの？
Yep. That's who your father is.
（ファバロ）
ああ それが お前の父親だ
My old man... My husband...
オヤジ… だんな…
No. Your father.
（ファバロ）
いや そこは“お父さん”だろ
My father...
（アーミラ）
おとうさん…
Wh-What the...
な… なんだあ？
（シーパー）
お話し中 申し訳ないが
Sorry to interrupt...
but it's time for you to jump ship.
そろそろ
船から降りてもらおうか
What do you mean?!
どういうことだ？
We'll be takin' all your valuable stuff now.
（シーパー）
金目のものは全て頂く
I bet the li'l gal will fetch an especially nice price.
その娘っ子は
とりわけ高く売れそうだ
海賊？
Pirates?
I see. So that's what this is about.
なるほど そういうことか
You can curse your misfortune all you want on the sea floor.
（シーパー）
海の底で己の運のなさを呪うんだな
（手下）
いやああ！
B-Bastard!
こ… この野郎！
ぐわっ！
That's enough, bounty hunter.
（シーパー）
そこまでだ 賞金稼ぎ
Drop the sword!
剣を捨てろ！
It seems like you're shit outta luck.
（シーパー）
やはり お前は
運がなかったようだな
I'd say you're the unlucky one.
（カイザル）
運が悪かったのは お前のほうだ
Huh?
A-A crab?!
カニ？
It looks tasty!
おいしそう！
Huh?!
It does have a nice boiled look to it, but...
確かに
よ～く茹(ゆ)で上がった色だが？
It's the Shipwrecker!
ヤツは船荒らしだ！
That thing's sunk countless ships!
何隻もの船が
あいつに沈められちまってる
（ファバロ）
何か武器はねえのか！
Where are your weapons?!
This is a cargo ship! We don't got anything like that on board!
（アモン）
貨物船だぞ
そんなもの積んじゃいねえ！
Run!
（ファバロ）
逃げろ！
あっ！　やっぱり？
I should've known!
（ケルベロス）
み～つけた
Found you!
Not tasty.
おいしくない
You don't say.
あっ そう…
Favaro, you're...
ファバロ お前…
I-It's a bit complicated, you see.
まっ まあ いろいろと複雑な事情が
ハッハッハ…
（アモン）
その尻尾と関係あんのか？
Does it have anything to do with that tail?
Tail?
（ファバロ）
尻尾？
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Don't get the wrong idea!
おいおい おいおい！
勘違いすんなよ
この尻尾は…
This tail isn't—
Color me shocked.
驚いたぜ
ヘッ お前も悪魔だったなんてな
I had no idea you were a demon, too.
"Too"?
（ファバロ）
“も”？
（アーミラ）あっ…
（アモン）動くな！
Don't move!
ぐお…
（アモン）
じっとしてろよ お嬢ちゃん
Just stay right where you are, missy.
Amon, you son of a bitch!
アモン てめえ…
I had a bit of a career change.
（アモン）
鞍(くら)替えしたのさ
I went from being a thief... to being a demon!
盗賊から…
悪魔にな
ヘッヘッヘ
It was all planned from the beginning, Favaro.
全て仕組まれてたんだよ ファバロ
Lidfard's execution for failing to protect the jewels...
警護に失敗したリドファルドが
死刑になったのも
Barossa and his men getting slaughtered by a demon after stealing them...
魔石を盗んだバロッサたちが
悪魔に殺されたのも
That same demon granted me magic powers in exchange for making it all happen.
裏で事を進めた見返りに
俺は その悪魔から
魔力を授けてもらったってわけさ
You betrayed... my old man?
裏切ったのか？　親父を
I ain't cut out to be an honorable thief, either.
俺も義賊なんてガラじゃねえ
He was too much of a goody-goody for me.
盗賊のくせに
ご立派すぎた あの男には
It was suffocating being around him, I gotta say.
心底 息が詰まる思いだったぜ
So I was surprised when I heard you showed up at the port.
だから 港に
お前が現れたって聞いたときは
驚いたね
Now I get to profit off of father and son!
親子そろって稼がせてくれるとはな
What?!
それにしても お前のツレ
Still, that gal pal of yours has got a serious bounty on her head.
えらく高い賞金が
かかってるじゃねえか
Just who is she?
一体 何者(なにもん)だ？
（ファバロ）
知らねえよ！　ただの他人だ
Hell if I know! Just some girl!
That so? I guess I don't need you anymore, then.
（アモン）
そうか　なら もう用はないな
Run! Run!
逃げろ！　逃げろ！
逃げろ！
Run!
Easier said than done!
むちゃ言うな！
But I won't go down without trying!
まっ でも 努力だけはよ…
You can control zombies without your spell book?!
（カイザル）
魔導書なしで
ゾンビを操れるのか？
Unfortunately, there's more than one tool for the job.
あいにく
道具は１つだけじゃないの
Also, how are you still
able-minded even as a zombie?!
（カイザル）
というか なぜ お前だけは
ゾンビになっても意識が…
（リタ）
飛ばすわよ
Hold on tight!
（アモン）
ゴホッ…
Damn, where did he go?!
野郎 どこに行きやがった！
逃がすな！　追え！
After 'em! Don't let 'em escape!
（カイザル）
ファバロ～！
Favaro!
Where are you, Favaro?!
どこにいる？
ファバロ～！
Kaisar?!
（ファバロ）
カイザル？
Y-You...
おっ お前…
Aren't you Lidfard's son?!
まさか リドファルドの？
Who in the blazes are you?!
なんだ 貴様は！
You're a bounty hunter, too?!
こっちも賞金稼ぎか
だが ヤツらは俺の獲物だ！
Those two are mine, though!
（ファバロ）
何が どうなってんだ？
What the hell's going on now?!
Favaro!
（アモン）
ファバロ！
Hand over the girl!
その女を渡せ！
（ファバロ）
よっと…
He's mine!
俺の相手だ
お前の親父が嫌いだったものを
知ってるか？
Know what your old man hated most?
Crooked aristocrats, authorities, and demons!
（ファバロ）
あくどい貴族や権力者
そして 悪魔だ！
That's why he refused to learn about magic...
だから 魔力は絶対に学ばなかった
で… してやられたのさ
and wound up dead!
Just like this!
（アモン）
こんなふうになあ！
You idiot! That could've killed me!
バッカ野郎 死ぬじゃねえかよ
ヘヘ… 終わりだよ ファバロ
This is the end, Favaro.
You can curse your bad luck, just as Barossa did!
バロッサ同様
自分の運のなさを恨め
Actually, the bad luck...
運がねえのは…
is all yours!
お前のほうさ！
おわっ！
What are you doing?! Let go!
何をする！　放せ！
放せ～！
Let go of me!
（ファバロ）
あばよ
So long.
I managed to con four suckers today! This must be my lucky day!
カモを４人も引っ掛けられるとは
今日はツイてたぜ
（バッカス）
おっと…
Hey! Watch where y—
おい！　気をつけろ…
（バッカス）
はいっ！
ハンサ 今 何か言ったか？
Did you just say something, Hansa?
（ハンサ）
くわ～
I gave 'em a lift here to keep 'em from attracting any attention.
（バッカス）
こそこそ のぞかれてんのも
目障りだから
Demons!
あいつらを
ここまで送ってやったが…
Fishmen! Fishmen everywhere!
（人々の悲鳴）
（男Ｃ）魚人が倒れてんぞ！
（バッカス）ヘッ…
（ハンス）くわ
But it was a waste of a trip, it seems.
（バッカス）
どうやら ムダ足だったみてえだな
（ファバロ）
よっと…
Favaro!
（カイザル）
ファバロ～！
It's time for me to settle things once and for all!
（カイザル）
今日こそは…
決着をつける！
ホント しつけえヤツだな
Man, you just don't know when to quit.
マ… マジか
Wh-What the hell?
Now, then. Come to me.
さあ 来い
Lady Amira!
（カイザル）
アーミラ嬢！
Amira!
アーミラ！　カイザル！
Kaisar!
My destiny,
sotto oshiete hoshii
won't you tell me?
aenai
But you're gone
ima wa tooi place to be
in a place so far away
unmei wa kawaru to
"Fate changes"
oshietekureta the truth is free
That's what you told me, and now the truth is free
I miss you
I revere you
You're my everything
I will follow you
subete wa ano toki
It all began then
To the promised land
tsuretette
So take me
yakusoku no basho e
to the promised land
It looks like we have an extra guest.
（ケルベロス）
余計なのが ついてきちゃったわね
Kill him, woof!
（メス犬）
殺しちゃえワン
（オス犬）
バーベキューだワン
Barbecue him, woof!
（アザゼル）待て
（ケルベロス）ん？
Wait.
もっと面白いものを見せてやる
I'll put on an even better show.
You're hiding something from me!
（ファバロ）俺に隠し事あるだろ？
（カイザル）そんなものはない
No, I'm not!
Don't play dumb! You wanna do the preview solo!
（ファバロ）
とぼけんでねえよ
予告 ピンでやりてえんだろ？
Hogwash!
Hmph. Nonsense.
（カイザル）
フッ 何を…
On the next Rage of Bahamut: Genesis,
"Rescue in Sword Valley."
次回「神撃(しんげき)のバハムート GENESIS(ジェネシス)」
Rescue(レスキュー) in(イン) Sword(ソード) Valley(バレー)
Happy?
（ファバロ）気が済んだか？
（カイザル）はい！
Yes!
Illustration:
Let's Bahamut to the max again next week!
Bahamut to the max!